<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Mengyue Han</title>
    <link>https://zhhmyz.github.io/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Mengyue Han</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://zhhmyz.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>HW7 : Deep learning model to classify insect images</title>
      <link>https://zhhmyz.github.io/project/assignment7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zhhmyz.github.io/project/assignment7/</guid>
      <description>Source data and code  Insect images Access to the github Source code  How does neural network works  The human eye sees an image as a set of signials, interpreted by the brain visual cortex. In the process of neural network image classification, images are turned into a series of vectors that depict physical objects and features. Computer vision systems analyze these constructs by simplifying images and extracting the most important information, then organzing data through feature extraction and classification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HW6 : Dashboard visualization of US PhDs</title>
      <link>https://zhhmyz.github.io/project/assignment6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zhhmyz.github.io/project/assignment6/</guid>
      <description>Source data and code  Science &amp;amp; Engineering Doctorates provides tables about detailed data on doctorate recipients such as demographic characteristics etc. Access to the Source code  Task  Do some analysis in pandas on the data and make dashboard visualization using dash I will use table12 that summarizes doctorate recipients by major field of study in year 1987-2017  Data analysis  Download and read the data into a dataframe  import pandas as pd df = pd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HW5 : Find the oldest person in Star Wars API</title>
      <link>https://zhhmyz.github.io/project/assignment5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zhhmyz.github.io/project/assignment5/</guid>
      <description>Source data and code  Star Wars API provides a good resource to practice with HTTP requests. Access to the Source code  1. Find the oldest person(or robot or alien) import requests import json import pandas as pd person = [] for i in range(1,83): p = requests.get(&amp;#34;https://swapi.dev/api/people/{}&amp;#34;.format(i)).json() person.append(p) df = pd.json_normalize(person) Take a sample of the data we read in, we can observe that the age is determined by the column birth_year birth_year is expressed as number + BBY(ABY), where BBY(ABY) represents Before the Battle of Yavin or After the Battle of Yavin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HW4 : Create sqlite3 schema of Spotify Songs dataset in 3rd normal form (3NF)</title>
      <link>https://zhhmyz.github.io/project/assignment4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zhhmyz.github.io/project/assignment4/</guid>
      <description>Source data and code  The Spotify Web API provides artist, album, playlist, track and audio features data. Source Code of this blog  Database normalization  Normalization is usually performed for reducing redundancy and preventing inconsistencies. Three normal forms should be completed after the data normalization process.  First Normal Form (1NF)  Table has primary key No composite values in each cell No repeating columns  Get access to the data</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HW3 : Informative visualizations about malaria</title>
      <link>https://zhhmyz.github.io/project/assignment3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zhhmyz.github.io/project/assignment3/</guid>
      <description>In this assignment, I will create 3 informative visualizations about malaria data using Python.
Source data and code   Malaria dataset contains three tables: Malaria incidence and deaths by country, deaths by age across the world and time.
  You can access to the source code for visualizations here: Github
  Informative visualizations 1. Malaria deaths across time in China I created a lineplot using seaborn to depict the overall death caused by malaria from 1990-2015 in China.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HW2 : Solve three problems from Euler Project</title>
      <link>https://zhhmyz.github.io/project/assignment2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zhhmyz.github.io/project/assignment2/</guid>
      <description>In this assignment, I will solve 3 problems from the Euler Project using Python. You can access the source code here: https://github.com/zhhmyz/BIOS-823
Problem 13: Large Sum Work out the first ten digits of the sum of the following one-hundread 50-digit numbers.
  Solved by 225065
  Link: https://projecteuler.net/problem=13
  nums = &amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;#34; one-hundred 50-digit numbers &amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;#34; def large_sum(a): &amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;#34;Sum 50-digit numbers and return the first ten digits Parameters ---------- a : string A one-hundred numbers string that is separated by &amp;#39;\n&amp;#39; Returns ------- int First ten digits of the calculation &amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;#34; a = a.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>